Administrator:
WELL, IT’S ABOUT TIME.
I KNEW THAT, IF I TORMENTED
THESE CHILDREN LONG ENOUGH,
YOU’D EMERGE FROM
YOUR MUSTY HOLE SOONER OR LATER.
Cardinal: HMPH!
TIME HAS BEEN KIND TO YOU.
IF I DIDN’T KNOW BETTER,
YOU COULD ALMOST PASS FOR HUMAN.
Administrator: MY, MY.
HOW CAVALIER YOU’VE BECOME.
YOU WERE NOTHING LIKE THIS
THE LAST TIME I SAW YOU,
LITTLE ONE.
YOU WERE SO TIMID.
WHY, WHEN YOU STOOD BEFORE ME
TWO CENTURIES AGO, YOUR TEETH
COULDN’T STOP CHATTERING.
REMEMBER, LYSERITH?
Cardinal: DO NOT CALL ME
BY THAT NAME, QUINELLA!
MY NAME IS CARDINAL.
I AM A PROGRAM WITH
ONE DIRECTIVE, DELETING YOU.
( Administrator laughs )
THAT’S RIGHT. YOU ARE.
HOWEVER, MY NAME
IS ADMINISTRATOR,
AND MY DIRECTIVE
IS TO MANAGE ALL PROGRAMS.
I’M SORRY IT TOOK SO LONG
FOR US TO MEET AGAIN.
BUT, YOU SEE, I WAS PREPARING
A SPECIAL ART TO WELCOME YOU,
AND FINISHING IT
TOOK LONGER THAN EXPECTED.
( Kirito gasps )
♪
Cardinal: DAMN YOU!
YOU CUT THE ADDRESS LOOSE.
Administrator: I CAME SO CLOSE
TO KILLING YOU 200 YEARS AGO,
BUT I LET YOU
SLIP THROUGH MY FINGERS,
AND I WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THAT DIDN’T HAPPEN AGAIN.
( snaps fingers )
SO...
I LEARNED FROM MY MISTAKE
AND CAME UP WITH A PLAN.
ALL I HAD TO DO
WAS LURE YOU OUT AGAIN
AND TRAP YOU
ON THIS SIDE WITH ME,
LIKE A MOUSE
IN THE SAME CAGE WITH A CAT.
Cardinal: AT THIS POINT,
IT IS NOT CLEAR
WHO IS THE MOUSE
AND WHO IS THE CAT.
YOU ARE TRAPPED IN HERE AS WELL.
AND, AS YOU CAN PLAINLY SEE,
THERE ARE FOUR OF US
AND ONLY ONE OF YOU.
Administrator:
FOUR AGAINST ONE, YOU SAY?
HARDLY! YOUR NUMBERS ARE OFF
BY A WIDE MARGIN, LITTLE ONE.
Cardinal: WHAT?
♪
Administrator: IN FACT--
AND THIS DOES NOT
INCLUDE MYSELF, MIND YOU--
IT’S FOUR AGAINST 300.
Kirito: 300 WHAT?
( gasps )
Cardinal: YOU VILE MONSTER.
IS THERE NO LIMIT
TO YOUR DEPRAVITY?
YOUR DUTY IS
TO PROTECT YOUR SUBJECTS,
AND YOU TURNED THEM INTO THAT?!
Eugeo: WAIT. "SUBJECTS"?
THAT THING...
Alice: THEN, THAT MONSTER,
AT ITS CORE, IS HUMAN?
Administrator:
YOU SAY SUCH SILLY THINGS
ABOUT TRIFLES SUCH AS DUTIES
AND SUBJECTS TO PROTECT.
I AM A CONQUEROR.
I HAVE NO PROBLEM,
AS LONG AS WHATEVER I RULE OVER
REMAINS SUBSERVIENT
AND OBEYS MY WILL.
WHETHER THEY BE SWORD OR HUMAN
MATTERS NOT TO ME.
( Cardinal gasps )
YOU HORRID--
Administrator:
OH, NOW, DON’T TELL ME
YOU’RE SHOCKED
THAT I USED A LITTLE THING
LIKE MATTER CONVERSION
ON HUMAN UNITS.
IT WAS ONLY A MEASLY 300 OR SO.
Cardinal: YOU ARE EVIL.
Administrator: THIS ONE IS
JUST A PROTOTYPE, BY THE WAY.
IN ORDER TO MASS-PRODUCE
THE FINAL VERSION
IN SUFFICIENT NUMBERS
TO HANDLE THE STRESS TEST,
I EXPECT I WILL NEED,
OH, ABOUT HALF.
Cardinal: HALF OF WHAT?
Administrator: WHY, NATURALLY
OF THE 80,000 HUMAN UNITS
LIVING IN THE HUMAN EMPIRE.
YES, THAT AMOUNT
SHOULD BE ENOUGH, I THINK,
TO REPEL THE ARMIES
OF THE DARK TERRITORY
AND TAKE THE FIGHT
BACK TO THEIR SIDE.
( all gasp )
Administrator: WELL? I HOPE THAT
ALLAYS YOUR FEARS, LITTLE ALICE.
YOUR PRECIOUS HUMAN EMPIRE
WILL BE MORE THAN PROTECTED.
Alice: MADAM PONTIFEX,
IT IS CLEAR MY WORDS
CANNOT REACH YOU NOW.
THEREFORE, AS A FELLOW
SACRED-ARTS USER,
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW
WHERE THE OWNERS ARE
OF THE 30 SWORDS YOU FASHIONED
THAT MONSTROSITY OUT OF.
EVEN IF YOU FLOUTED THE RULE
ALLOWING PERFECT CONTROL
OVER ONE WEAPON,
PONTIFEX OR NO,
YOU CANNOT BREAK THE NEXT RULE.
TO ACTIVATE MEMORY RELEASE,
THERE MUST BE A BOND BETWEEN
THE WEAPON AND ITS OWNER.
PONTIFEX, IF YOU
TRULY USED INNOCENT HUMANS
AS THE SOURCE OF THE BLADES
WHICH MAKE UP THAT THING,
THERE IS NO WAY THEY
WOULD FORM A BOND WITH YOU!
Administrator: THE EXPLANATION
IS HIDING IN PLAIN SIGHT,
MY DEAR.
EUGEO SEEMS TO HAVE
ALREADY DISCOVERED IT.
( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: NO. NO!
WHAT?
Eugeo: SEE THE CRYSTALS
ON THE CEILING?
THEY’RE NOT DECORATIONS.
THEY’RE WHAT SHE STOLE
FROM THE KNIGHTS
WITH THE SYNTHESIS RITUAL.
THOSE ARE THEIR MEMORIES!
( both gasp )
Cardinal: CURSE YOU,
QUINELLA, YOU FIEND!
TOYING LIKE THIS WITH THE HUMANS
IS BEYOND TWISTED!
YOU PLACED
THE MEMORY FRAGMENTS YOU STOLE
INTO MENTAL MODELS
ON FRESH LIGHTCUBES.
THAT IS ALL IT WOULD TAKE TO
CREATE SIMULATED HUMAN BEINGS.
BUT THEIR INTELLIGENCE
WOULD BE SEVERELY LIMITED,
AND THEY WOULD
NOT BE ABLE TO EXECUTE
AN ADVANCED COMMAND
SUCH AS PERFECT WEAPON CONTROL.
BUT YOU CAN GET AROUND THAT
IF THE MEMORY FRAGMENT
AND THE WEAPON IT IS LINKED TO
SHARE THE SAME STRUCTURAL DATA.
THE MEMORIES OF PEOPLE
THE KNIGHTS ONCE HELD DEAR,
THE MEMORIES YOU STOLE
AND CARVED ONTO THESE CRYSTALS,
THEY ARE
WHAT YOUR GOLEM IS MADE OF!
ISN’T THAT RIGHT?!
Administrator: THESE ARTIFICIAL
PERSONAS DESIRE BUT ONE THING,
TO FIND THE ONE THEY REMEMBER,
TOUCH THEM, HOLD THEM,
POSSESS THEM.
UNSEEMLY DESIRE
COURSES THROUGHOUT THIS PUPPET
AND PROVIDES ITS MOTIVATION.
THEY SENSE THE ONES
THEY REMEMBER ARE NEAR,
BUT THEY CANNOT TOUCH THEM.
THEY CANNOT BE ONE WITH THEM.
THEIR THIRST
FOR THAT CONNECTION DRIVES THEM
TO THE POINT OF MADNESS,
BUT ALL THEY CAN SEE NOW
ARE THE ENEMIES
STANDING IN THEIR WAY.
THEY THINK,
IF THEY CAN DESTROY YOU,
THE ONE THEY DESIRE
WILL BECOME THEIRS.
THAT IS WHY THEY FIGHT.
AND, NO MATTER
HOW BADLY THEY’RE WOUNDED
OR HOW MANY TIMES THEY FALL,
THEY’LL KEEP FIGHTING
FOR ETERNITY.
I DESIGNED IT
RATHER WELL, DID I NOT?
THE POWER OF DESIRE
CAN ACHIEVE GREAT THINGS
IF HARNESSED PROPERLY.
Cardinal: YOU’RE WRONG!
DON’T YOU DARE
TARNISH THAT EMOTION
BY CALLING IT DESIRE!
WHAT THEY FEEL IS--
IS PURE LOVE!
Administrator:
WELL, NOW YOU’RE
JUST SPLITTING HAIRS,
LITTLE ONE.
LOVE IS CONTROL.
LOVE IS DESIRE.
EITHER WAY, IT IS A SIGNAL
PRODUCED BY A FLUCTLIGHT,
NOTHING MORE,
WHICH BRINGS US
TO AN EVEN GREATER REVELATION.
( chuckles )
NOW THAT YOU KNOW THE TRUTH
ABOUT MY FEARSOME PUPPET,
YOU CANNOT DESTROY IT,
BECAUSE...
EVERY SINGLE BLADE
IS A LIVING HUMAN BEING
WHO HAS BEEN TRANSFORMED
INTO A SWORD.
( Cardinal gasping )
YES, YOU’RE RIGHT.
I CANNOT KILL A HUMAN.
I SPENT THE PAST 200 YEARS
HONING AN ART TO KILL YOU
AND YOUR INHUMAN FORM,
BUT IT WAS ALL FOR NOTHING.
( Administrator laughs )
YOU ARE SUCH A FOOL!
IT’S BOTH FUNNY AND TRAGIC!
YOU KNEW THAT ALL LIFE
IN THIS WORLD
WAS JUST A COLLECTION OF DATA
THAT CAN BE REWRITTEN,
AND YET YOU TREAT IT AS HUMAN.
Cardinal: I DID,
BECAUSE THEY ARE HUMAN.
THE PEOPLE OF THE UNDERWORLD
HAVE THE EMOTIONS
YOU AND I LOST, QUINELLA.
THEY CAN LAUGH, GRIEVE,
FEEL JOY AND LOVE.
THAT IS WHAT MAKES THEM HUMAN.
( groans )
I WILL LET YOU TAKE MY LIFE.
BUT FIRST I WANT YOUR WORD
THAT YOU WILL SPARE
THESE YOUNG ONES!
Kirito: NO! YOU CAN’T--
♪
Administrator: OUT OF CURIOSITY,
LET US SAY
I ACCEPTED YOUR OFFER.
WHAT WOULD I STAND
TO GAIN FROM IT?
Cardinal: IF YOU
DECIDE TO FIGHT,
I WILL NOT ONLY KEEP
YOUR PATHETIC PUPPET AT BAY,
I WILL SHAVE OFF AT LEAST
HALF OF YOUR LIFE AS WELL.
THE LOSS OF THAT WOULD PUT
AN EVEN GREATER STRAIN
ON YOUR ALREADY DWINDLING
MEMORY CAPACITY, WOULD IT NOT?
Administrator: HMM.
VERY WELL, THEN.
LETTING THEM GO NOW
GIVES ME SOMETHING
TO LOOK FORWARD TO LATER. HEH!
ALL RIGHT. I SWEAR
ON THE GODDESS STACIA,
- AFTER I KILL--
- Cardinal: NO, NOT ON A GOD.
YOU’LL SWEAR ON THE ONE THING
YOU VALUE MOST,
YOUR FLUCTLIGHT,
OR THE DEAL IS OFF.
Administrator: FINE, FINE.
I HEREBY SWEAR
ON MY FLUCTLIGHT
AND ALL THE PRECIOUS DATA
I’VE ACCUMULATED UP TO NOW,
AFTER I’VE KILLED YOU,
LITTLE ONE,
I SHALL ALLOW THOSE THREE
TO ESCAPE UNHARMED.
Cardinal: YOU HAD BETTER.
( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal: I AM SORRY.
Administrator: HMPH.
( Cardinal grunts )
( chuckles )
WAS THAT YOUR BEST?
FIRE ALL YOU WANT. I--
( gasping )
Administrator: I’M HOLDING BACK
FOR NOW, LITTLE ONE.
AFTER ALL, WHAT FUN WOULD IT BE
IF I DISPATCHED YOU QUICKLY?
I HAVE BEEN WAITING
200 YEARS FOR THIS MOMENT!
( Cardinal groans )
( shrieks )
( Administrator chuckling )
( laughing )
- ( Kirito growls )
- Cardinal: STAY BACK!
Eugeo: I CAN’T HELP.
ALL I CAN DO IS
STAND HERE POWERLESS.
( gasps )
THINK!
THERE HAS TO BE
SOMETHING I CAN DO.
INSTEAD OF WHINING
ABOUT BEING WEAK,
FIND A WAY TO FIGHT BACK.
Administrator: NOW TO FINISH
OUR CENTURIES-LONG GAME.
FAREWELL, DEAR LYSERITH.
FAREWELL, MY ONLY DAUGHTER.
FAREWELL...
MY OTHER SELF!
( chuckles )
( laughing )
♪
Kirito: SORRY. I’M SO SORRY.
Cardinal: NO NEED TO APOLOGIZE.
YOU STILL HAVE A MISSION...
TO FULFILL, DON’T YOU?
THE THREE OF YOU,
SAVE THIS WORLD,
FRAGILE, BEAUTIFUL.
Alice: WE WILL, NO MATTER WHAT.
YOU HAVE GIVEN ME
A SECOND CHANCE,
AND I SHALL USE IT
TO DEFEND THIS WORLD.
( crying )
- Girl: EUGEO...
- ( Eugeo gasps )
THAT’S IT.
I FINALLY FIGURED IT OUT.
I KNOW WHAT MY PURPOSE
IS SUPPOSED TO BE.
I’M NOT GOING TO RUN AWAY.
I’M GOING TO STAY
AND FULFILL MY DUTY.
( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: PLEASE, CARDINAL,
WITH WHATEVER STRENGTH
YOU HAVE LEFT,
I WANT YOU
TO TURN ME INTO A SWORD...
JUST LIKE HER PUPPET.
♪
( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal: EUGEO, YOU CAN’T...
Eugeo: EVEN IF SHE LETS US GO,
ADMINISTRATOR WILL STILL CHANGE
HALF THE PEOPLE INTO GOLEMS.
WE CAN’T LET HER
DO THAT TO THEM.
IF THERE’S ANY CHANCE LEFT
TO STOP HER,
ANY HOPE LEFT AT ALL,
THIS SACRED ART MUST BE IT.
SYSTEM CALL.
REMOVE CORE PROTECTION.
GO AHEAD NOW. CHANGE ME.
THE BOND BETWEEN US IS STRONG,
MUCH STRONGER
THAN HER AND THAT MONSTER’S.
Kirito: STOP IT! DON’T DO THIS.
Eugeo: IT’S OKAY.
THIS IS WHAT I WAS MEANT TO DO.
Cardinal: VERY WELL, EUGEO.
THE FINAL ART I CAST IN LIFE
WILL GO TOWARD YOUR OBJECTIVE.
Eugeo: HOLD ON. BEFORE I GO,
I NEED TO TELL YOU
ONE LAST THING.
METAL WEAPONS DON’T WORK
ON THE PONTIFEX.
THAT’S WHY I COULDN’T
STAB HER WITH MY DAGGER.
( Kirito sighs )
♪
Administrator: NOW WHAT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU’RE DOING?!
WOULD YOU DIE, ALREADY?!
Alice: NO, YOU DON’T!
♪
( groans )
YOUR LIGHTNING
WILL NOT WORK ON ME!
Administrator:
YOU INSOLENT LITTLE KNIGHT.
HOW DARE YOU DEFY ME?
I SHALL BURN
ALL THREE OF YOU TO CINDERS!
Alice: AND I
SHALL STOP YOU AGAIN!
( grunts )
( chorus vocalizing )
- ( gasps )
- ( Administrator gasps )
Cardinal: RELEASE RECOLLECTION.
♪
Administrator:
YOU CAN MIMIC MY SPELL, FOOL.
HOWEVER, ONE PALTRY SWORD
IS NO MATCH
AGAINST MY GOLEM OF 30 BLADES.
IT WILL SNAP IT IN HALF
WITH A SINGLE BLOW!
Cardinal: HUMAN LOVE, BEAUTIFUL.
THE SHINING LIGHT OF PURPOSE,
SO BEAUTIFUL.
Kirito: YEAH. IT IS.
Cardinal: KIRITO, I MUST GO NOW.
PROTECT THIS WORLD, ITS PEOPLE.
I LEAVE IT TO YOU.
♪
( Administrator gasps )
Kirito: EUGEO.
Administrator: WELL, WELL.
YOU WANT TO FIGHT SOME MORE,
LITTLE BOY?
DO NOT MAKE THE MISTAKE
OF BECOMING OVERCONFIDENT
JUST BECAUSE
YOU DEMOLISHED MY PUPPET.
Kirito: DON’T DO IT.
DON’T GO.
EUGEO!
( Administrator laughs )
Kirito: EUGEO!
Administrator:
YOU WRETCHED BRAT!
( Kirito gasps )
( cracking )
( Administrator gasps )
( yells )
♪
( Kirito gasps )
( gasping )
Administrator:
I DID NOT SEE THAT COMING.
IN TERMS OF PRIORITY LEVEL,
THE SWORD THAT FUSED WITH EUGEO
WAS NO MATCH FOR MY BLADE,
THE SILVERY ETERNITY.
BUT I DID NOT REALIZE
HIS SWORD WAS NOT METALLIC.
THAT WAS MY MISTAKE.
WHAT A BOTHER.
SO, IT SEEMS YOU ARE
THE LAST ONE STANDING.
SURPRISING, TO SAY THE LEAST,
BOY FROM THE OTHER SIDE.
I AM STILL CURIOUS
AS TO WHY YOU’RE HERE
WITHOUT
ADMINISTRATOR PRIVILEGES,
ALTHOUGH, AT THIS POINT,
IT DOESN’T MATTER.
( blows )
NOW THE FIGHT IS OVER,
I’M SLEEPY.
I’LL ASK THE OTHER BOY
FROM THE OUTER WORLD
WHY YOU WERE HERE
AFTER I FILL MY CHAMBER
WITH YOUR BLOOD AND SCREAMS.
THIS IS THE END, BOY.
PERHAPS WE WILL
MEET AGAIN SOMEDAY
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
♪
( Kirito gasps )
IT’S HAPPENING AGAIN.
I’M LETTING IT HAPPEN AGAIN.
Cardinal: YOU DO NOT
HAVE TO WIN ALL THE TIME,
AND, IF YOU LOSE,
WHAT DOES IT EVEN MATTER?
IN THE END, WHAT DOES
IS THAT YOUR HEART
AND WILL ARE REMEMBERED.
I AM CERTAIN EVERYONE
WHO HAS SPENT TIME WITH YOU
AND MOVED ON TO OTHER PLANES
BELIEVED THAT,
AS DO I.
WE HAVE GIVEN YOU
THE STRENGTH TO STAND,
SO STAND AND
PROTECT THOSE YOU HOLD DEAR.
♪
( Kirito grunts )
Alice: WELL, NOW,
YOU CAN MOVE, CAN’T YOU?
Kirito: YEAH.
I CAN TAKE IT FROM HERE.
Alice: IF YOU WISH.
HAVE AT IT.
♪
( chorus vocalizing )
Kirito: YOU FOUGHT HARD, ALICE,
AND NOW IT’S MY TURN.
CHARLOTTE, CARDINAL, AND EUGEO,
THEY GAVE THEIR LIVES FOR MINE.
NOW I’LL GIVE MINE FOR YOURS.
( Administrator giggles )
( singing in Japanese )
♪
♪ PROUD OF MYSELF ♪